Travis Whitten

traviswhitten.com | Atlanta, GA 30318 | (770) 561-3305 | contact@traviswhitten.com

Skills

Software: Proficient in software programming in C, C++, and Assembly, and have experience with BIOS/UEFI firmware development, Docker, Git/GitLab, Python, C#, Java, Verilog, LabVIEW, Unity3D, and HTML/CSS.

Hardware: Proficient in circuit design and logic design with experience in development for Arduino and Motorola 68HC11 microcontrollers and Xilinx FPGA. Experienced in prototyping and development in the lab with the use of electronics test equipment.

Work Experience

FIRMWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER | AMI (AMERICAN MEGATRENDS) | DULUTH, GA | JUNE 2021 - PRESENT

- · Developed and improved various x86 UEFI firmware components, included DXE driver components and EFI applications.
- · Participated in review and submission of changes to core code to address bugs, gaps in code quality, or additional functionality.
- · Assisted with development and troubleshooting of cloud development platform utilizing GitLab and Docker

FIELD APPLICATION ENGINEER | AMI (AMERICAN MEGATRENDS) | DULUTH, GA | JUNE 2019 - JUNE 2021

- · Created, maintained, and presented informative and engaging materials to describe new products and features and demonstrate their capabilities to current and potential customers.
- · Presented internal training materials to sales teams and other employees throughout multiple regions.
- · Assisted in development, testing, and tracking of new products and features including software engineering efforts, hardware setup, and troubleshooting throughout the product life cycle.
- · Facilitated the flow of technical information from engineering roles to non-engineering roles in an easily understandable way.
- · Participated in various firmware industry forums and active working groups as a liaison of AMI.
- · Created presentation materials for and hosted/presented at the 2020 AMI European Summit webinar series.
- · Trained in x86 UEFI firmware development, including bus interfaces, PEI driver, DXE driver, and EFI application development.

IT SUPPORT STAFF | UGA COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING | ATHENS, GA | AUGUST 2015 - MAY 2019

- · Developed and maintained the use of a K2000 systems deployment environment, used to set up new college computers quickly and uniformly, reducing deployment time and employee resources by more than 50%.
- · Led the training of 3 new student workers in the scope of their responsibilities and use of various tools, software, and the K2000.
- · Provided hardware and software support for classrooms and labs for faculty, staff, and students.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF GEORGIA | MAY 2019 | ATHENS, GA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Systems Engineering

Related coursework: Embedded Systems Design, Design of Digital Systems, Advanced Digital Design, Sensors and Transducers, Electrical Circuits, Systems Programming, Data Structures, Computer Networks

Projects

Senior Capstone Design Project with Gulfstream

- · Collaborated with Gulfstream Aerospace Corporation to implement emerging virtual reality and eye-tracking technology.
- · Developed test environments within Unity3D to track a user's gaze and migrated the eye-tracking functionality into a flight sim.
- · Developed a heat map generator within the virtual environment to conduct a study to visualize participants' gaze locations.